Finding Aid for Hubert N. Robinson Papers 1948-1984
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Hubert N. Robinson Papers 1948-1984
Robinson, Hubert Nelson, 1909-
1 linear ft., 2 oversize volumes, and 1 oversize folder
Bishop of the African Methodist Episcopal Church. Scattered correspondence, and clippings detailing his career, church programs and printed material; also photographs.
85355;AC;Aa 2;UAm
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection is the gift of Bishop Robinson and was given through Rev. Kenneth Hill (Donor No. 7123 ).
The collection is open for research.
Bishop Hubert N. Robinson was born in Urbana, Ohio in 1909. He received his A.B. from the Ohio State University and his B.D. from Hamma Divinity School at Wittenberg College. Robinson joined the Ohio Conference of the African Methodist Episcopal Church in 1930 and became an elder in 1934. His first pastorate was at Bellaire, Ohio and was followed by service at Cincinnati, Steubenville, and Columbus, Ohio; and Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. From 1948 to 1955 Robinson led the St. James A.M.E. Church in Cleveland, Ohio. In 1955, he was reassigned to Ebenezer in Detroit, Michigan.
Upon his appointment as a bishop in 1964, Robinson was assigned to the Eighteenth District in Africa, consisting of Lesotho, Swaziland, Botswana, and Mozambique. Transferred back to the United States in 1968, he served in Alabama, Florida, and the Bahamas.
In 1976, he was appointed presiding bishop of the Fourth District. The district includes the Canadian, Chicago, Illinois, Indiana, and Michigan Annual Conferences. Since taking over the Fourth District, Bishop Robinson has received many honors. He has served as president of both the A.M.E. Council of Bishops and General Board and as chairman of the General Conference Commission. In 1979, Ebony named Bishop Robinson one of the 100 outstanding Blacks in America.
The papers of Bishop Hubert N. Robinson are divided into six series: biographical, correspondence, clippings and scrapbooks, programs, A.M.E. printed material, and photographs.
Subjects:
African Methodist Episcopal Church.; African Americans--Michigan.; Clergy--United States.; Robinson, Hubert Nelson, 1909-
Subjects - Visual Material:
African Methodist Episcopal Church.; African Americans--Spiritual life.; Clergymen.; Graduation ceremonies.; Religious services.; Robinson, Hubert Nelson, 1909-; South Africa.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Biographical
  The Biographical series includes a printed biographical profile and awards from various civic organizations and municipalities.
  - Various information (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  Correspondence covers the period from 1950 to 1984 and is contained in one folder. It includes personal letters from friends and parishioners as well as official correspondence with other organizations.
  - 1950-1984 (Box 1)
- Clippings and Scrapbook
  - Clippings, 1950-1984
    - 1950-1959 (Box 1)
    - 1960-1969 (Box 1)
    - 1970-1979 (Box 1)
    - 1980-1984 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks
    The Ccrapbooks series consists of 2 volumes of clippings and miscellaneous material from Robinson's years as pastor of St. James in Cleveland.
    - 1948-1953 (Volume 1)
    - 1953-1955 (Volume 2)
- Programs (Box 1)
  - 1950-1984 (Box 1)
- A.M.E. Printed Material and Miscellanea
  - Quality of life centers, 4th Episcopal District, 1976-1984 (Box 1)
  - Report of the ad hoc committee for corrections and/or codifications of the 1980-1984 A.M.E. Discipline, Bishop Hubert N. Robinson, chairman (Box 1)
  - Michigan: contains booklets on, 1982 creative arts festival, Camp Baber, and 1963 North Ohio Conference (Box 1)
  - National (Box 1)
    (contains several booklets on the history and philosophy of the A.M.E. Church)
  - Swaziland and Bechuanaland: Minutes and notes (Box 1)
- Photographs
  Portraits; photos of Robinson and his family at farewell reception prior to trip to South Africa; photos of church services and ceremonies, and of honorary degree ceremonies for Robinson; and group photos of bishops of the A.M.E. Church.
  - Portrait; preaching in church; receiving honorary degree (Box 1)
  - Family and friends (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous
  - Bishops of A.M.E. Church, 1980-1984, August 1984